<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stats on Pietro&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/categories/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stats on Pietro&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene expression - microarray data still useful</title>
      <link>/2019/07/18/gene-expression-microarray-data-still-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/18/gene-expression-microarray-data-still-useful/</guid>
      <description>I work on pancreatic cancer -omics. Data mining on published data is a real source of gold today when someone wants to find confirmation of an hypothesis on a more general scale than his own dataset.
The most common -omics datasets out there are transcriptomics one; both RNA-Seq and good ol’ microarray. Regarding RNA-Seq, the well known TCGA and ICGC are my starting point for any explorative data mining analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize ggplot2 boxplots - make &#39;em beautiful</title>
      <link>/2019/07/15/customize-ggplot2-boxplots-make-em-beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/15/customize-ggplot2-boxplots-make-em-beautiful/</guid>
      <description>I like ggplot2 graphic style, but to make publication acceptable plots, especially to align with graphic style of some journals, sometimes it is necessary to customize plots and modify some parameters that usually are kept as default.
Here I will present some tricks to make beautiful - at least to me - boxplots. I am using the iris dataset, always the best to be reproducible for everyone.
First we define a function to make first letter of each word upper case, retrieved from here https://stackoverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove legend from ggplot2 plot</title>
      <link>/2018/09/08/remove-legend-from-ggplot2-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/08/remove-legend-from-ggplot2-plot/</guid>
      <description>Since I googled this thousands of times, I post it here to help me stick it into my mind.
To completely remove the legend from a ggplot2 graph, use this:
theme(legend.position = &#39;none&#39;)
If in your plot you are using a different theme from the default one, place the above code after the code for the theme, otherwise it will be replaced.
library(tidyverse) iris %&amp;gt;% ggplot(aes(Species, Sepal.Length, col = Species)) + geom_boxplot() # remove legend iris %&amp;gt;% ggplot(aes(Species, Sepal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>