<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pietro&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pietro&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I am a PhD candidate in Biotechnology at the University of Verona. Officially. But I prefer to consider myself as a newbie in everything. This means that I am very curious and I love to learn and discover new things.
Apart from the romanticisms, I like life sciences and as a PhD candidate in Biotechnology (plant genetics) my project aims at the identification of the genes involved in the regulation of flowering and veraison in grapevine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>/2018/09/05/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/05/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my new website which I intend to use it as a lab notebook where I share my research projects, ideas and R coding examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a website using blogdown, RMarkdown, Github and Netlify</title>
      <link>/2018/09/05/how-to-create-a-website-using-blogdown-rmarkdown-github-and-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/05/how-to-create-a-website-using-blogdown-rmarkdown-github-and-netlify/</guid>
      <description>I have to express gratitude to John Muschelli who recorded this useful and very fun video on how to create a website blog using RStudio, blogdown, Github and Netlify. Here is the link https://youtu.be/syWAKaj-4ck. Also I want to thank rbind.io community that provided me with a custom address at the rbind domain, which is very helpful if you want to deploy your blog at Netlify.com and you don’t have your custom address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal component analysis - the tidyverse way</title>
      <link>/2018/09/05/principal-component-analysis---the-tidyverse-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/05/principal-component-analysis---the-tidyverse-way/</guid>
      <description>PCA with any kind of data In my daily work I am often asked to perform Principal Component Analysis of various type of -omics data, for example data coming from RNA-Seq.
With this data usually the rows correspond to genes (transcripts, proteins, etc..) while columns are individuals or samples.
For example something like this, where I have mouse proteins in rows and mass spec peak intensities in columns, where each column is a different sample:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona
Strada Le Grazie 15, Verona
pietro.delfino (at) univr (dot) it

Born April 26, 1988 - Genova  RESEARCH EXPERIENCE May-November 2015 Laimburg Research Center - Researcher in the lab of Applied Genomics and Molecular Biology - Advisor: Dr. Thomas Letschka
December 2013-January 2015 ETH Zürich - Research Assistant at the Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Advisor: Prof. Bruno Studer
November 2012-November 2013 Fondazione Edmund Mach - MSc Internship in the Department of Genomics - Advisor: Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>